Guide to the Carolyn S. Schumacher Papers AIS.2011.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Pittsburgh Schools Research File, 1921-2001; 1978-1983; III.
  - Articles & Photocopies, 1921-1984; 2.
    - Department of Interior, "Organization of Research Bureaus in City School Systems" by Elise Martens from 1924 (copies), undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Detroit Public Schools Course of Study in the Use of the Library, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Digest of Educational Statistics (copy), 1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Education for Pittsburgh by Harvard Graduate School of Education, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Enrollment of M.T. Survey between 1889-1900 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Erasmus Wilson, "Private Schools," 1898 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Eric Johnson, Delinquency Talk at Duquesne, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - 1905 E.Z. Smith Pittsburgh Article (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Family Configuration and Intelligence, Science Magazine, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 50th Anniversary Newsletter, 1961 November (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "From Manual Training to Vocational Education: The Lowest Educational Track" by Carolyn Schumacher, Presented at Annual Meeting of American education research Association, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Haney and Zimbardo, School as Jail, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - High School Entrance Exam 1872 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - High School Entrance Exams in 1872-1900 (copies), undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - 1875 High School Examination (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - High School Programs in 1914 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - History of Schools circa 1928-1977 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Indiana Conference 1923 (copies), undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Industrial Education – Comparative 1914-1979 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Intercultural Education Through Home Economics, Industrial Arts, and Commercial Subjects, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - James Bonar 1926-1931 (copies), undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - James Mulhern, "A History of Secondary Education" from 1933 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - J.E. Wallin, "The Odyssey of a Psychologist" – Special Education 1955 (copy) and notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - John Morrow, (Superintendent Allegheny Public Schools), 1881, also reprinted from 18th Annual Report of Superintendent of Schools to Pittsburgh Board of Education 1896 Photocopy, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - 1895 Kelly Handbook of Greater Pittsburgh (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Lincoln 21st Ward News Article 1897 (copy), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - McCoy Xerox, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - "Microfilming School Records" by Herbert Popenoe, School Board Journal October 1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - The Mill Hunk Herald, Fall, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Names of Pittsburgh Schools in 1894, circa 1980 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Names of Schools in 1869-1926 (copies), undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - "New Directions in Educational Effort" by Cubberly 1934 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Newsweek Black Youth, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Nora Faires, Germans in Allegheny City, 1850-1860 (copy), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Number of Seats, Pittsburgh Schools, 1869-1900 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - "Occupational Groups in the U.S. 1820-1920" by Whelpton 1926 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - "Opposition to Progressive School Reform: The 1913 Pittsburgh School Children's Strike," by Douglas Shaw (University of Akron), 1978 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - "Ornamentation," by the New York Times Magazine, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Pennsylvania School Chronicle from 1870 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Pennsylvania School Journal on German Education from 1862 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Pennsylvania School Reports 1862-1930 (copies) and notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Pennsylvania Superintendents Reports between 1856-1890 (copies), undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Pittsburgh Board of Education Organization Manual, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Pittsburgh History, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Pittsburgh Public Schools: Geographic, Biography and Historic Pittsburgh, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Pittsburgh Public Schools Membership Reports, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Pittsburgh Public Schools Report on Intergroup Relations, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Pittsburgh Schools Alumni Register 1901 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Pittsburgh School Curriculum 1914-1928 (copies), undated (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Pittsburgh School Reports from 1869-1872 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Pittsburgh School Subdistricts 1873-1894 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Pittsburgh Schools by Thomas Baker, undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Pittsburgh Schools – What's in a Name 1959 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Pittsburgh Survey and Medical Inspection 1914 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Pittsburgh Survey in 1914 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Professional and Technical Staffing of Central Administration of Pittsburgh Board of Education, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Program for the Dedication of the Grandview School, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Progressive Education 1904 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - "Public Education in Pittsburgh 1835-1900" by William McCoy from 1951 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - 1933-1939 PWA Buildings (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Re: Entrance Exam, undated (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Re-Examination for Admission to the Pittsburgh Central High School Sept. 2, 1872 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Report of the Citizens Advisory Committee on Racial Equality and Education to the Board of Education Pittsburgh, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Russell Packard, "Some Present Tendencies in Secondary Education" from 1930, undated (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - School Building Architects, undated (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - School Buildings- Articles from 1888-1929 (copies), undated (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - School Census 1869-1917 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - School District Maps from 1868-1931(copies), undated (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - School Rooms 1912 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Schools/Wards/School Directors 1855-1870 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Standards and Affirmative Action Articles, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - The Stones of Pittsburgh, "By Any Other Name, The Controversial Spelling of Pittsburgh" or "Why the H" by James D. Van Tramp, Pittsburgh History and Landmarks Foundation, undated (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Teachers Certification and Exam 1872-1900 (copies) and notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Transcribed from Pittsburgh Index on H.C. Frick 1916 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Using the Library 1902 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Westinghouse History 1927 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - "What about Tomorrow?" M. M. Steen article 1947 and notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Where Board Meets- Condition of Pittsburgh Schools 1896 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - WPA Projects in 1938 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Research, 1940-2001; 1975-1983; 3.
    The Research subseries contains materials related to Schumacher's research about the Pittsburgh Schools in the late nineteenth and twentieth centuries, including her research notes, correspondence, bibliographies, directories, maps, newspaper clippings, surveys, and articles related to the history of education in the region as well as national educational issues.
    - African Americans and Education, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Archives of Industrial Society, 1949-1981 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Bedford School Project, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Bibliography on Pittsburgh Schools, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Birth Rate Newspaper Clipping, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Board Resolution, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Chronology, undated (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Closed Schools between 1897-1977, circa 1980 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Closed Schools Directory, undated (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - CMU Graduate Studies Mellon College of Science, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - CMU History 1901-1978, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Ileen A. DeVault (Yale History), 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence Journal Editors, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Crutes Notes, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Current Pittsburgh Statistics, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Diana Wood, CMU Analysis of Pittsburgh Schools, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Division of Research Inventory, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Education Bibliography, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Education Statistics, 1979 May (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Exam Books and Summary of Admissions notes for 1902-1911, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - 1902-1911 Exam Tally, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Fisher, Industrial Education Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Historical Society of Western PA, circa 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - History of Education Sources- England, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - History of Schools Clippings, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - High School Attendance, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Interviews with Vessely, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - IQ California Case, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - J.J. Livingston, Newspapers and Education, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Literacy, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Map of Pittsburgh Schools, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Maps of Schools, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Mental Health, circa 1967 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Mrs. Maxine Aaron, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - National Public School Statistics, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Nora's Analysis of Census 1850/1870, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Normal State Schools, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Notes on Current Central Admin, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Notes on Entrance Exam, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 100 Years in Pittsburgh Public Schools, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Park Place News Article, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Pennsylvania State Laws, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Pennsylvania Youth Survey, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Pitt Seminar Papers Bibliography, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Pittsburgh Bibliography, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Pittsburgh Ethnicity in 1860, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Pittsburgh History, circa 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Pittsburgh History and Landmarks, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Pittsburgh Magnet Schools, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Pittsburgh Neighborhood Fair, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Pittsburgh Public Schools Admin. Office Organization, 1955-1981 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Pittsburgh Public Schools Annual Report, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Pittsburgh Public School Personnel Directory, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Pittsburgh Schools- Addresses and Principals, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Pittsburgh School Board Reports/Minutes, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Pittsburgh Schools Designated Historic Structures, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Pittsburgh Schools, National Register Application, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Pittsburgh School Population Newsclipping, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - School Histories, 1975-1986; 4.
      The School Histories subseries contains materials related to Schumacher's research on the history of individual schools within the Pittsburgh School system in the late nineteenth and twentieth centuries including photocopies of primary materials and notes.
      - Allderdice, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - Allegheny High, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 80)
      - Beck's Run School, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 81)
      - Fifth, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - Franklin in May 1926 (copy), undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - Frick Training School Pittsburgh, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - Gladstone, undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - Grant School District in May 1926 (copy), undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - Larimer, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - Schenely, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 88)
      - Stephen Foster School, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - Washington Subdistrict notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 90)
      - Washington School, undated (Box 4, Folder 91)
      - Weber Charity School, undated (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - Westinghouse, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 93)
      - Wightman School, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Pittsburgh Survey, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Pittsburgh Townships and Boroughs, circa 1980 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Pittsburgh Wards, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Population Statistics Newsclippings, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Population Statistics, Older Population, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Preliminary Checklist to the Records of the Board of Education of the city of New York, Teachers College Library Archives, Columbia University, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Pupil Records- State Law, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Records Retention Schedule, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Research Bulletin Notes, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Research on Pittsburgh School Bulletins between 1908-1912, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - The Revisionists Revised, Politics of Education review, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Role of Education in Occupational Mobility, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Rollo Turner, Black Pittsburgh, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - School Architecture Notebook, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - School Attendance, Peggy's Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - School Board, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - School Buildings, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - School Chronology, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - School Closing Schedules, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - School Enrollment in the U.S., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - School House, Allegheny County, Greek Revival, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - School Prayer, Letter to Editor, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - School Research Materials/Notes, circa 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - School Statistics, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Strong Notes, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - A Study of School Holding Power, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Vocational Education, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Testing & Teacher Effectiveness, 1971-1983; 1978-1981; 5.
    The Testing & Teacher Effectiveness subseries contains photocopies of primary sources, notes, articles, newspaper clippings, and publications related to Schumacher's research about the means of testing in the Pittsburgh Public Schools in the late nineteenth and twentieth centuries, as well as research about teachers' education, certification, rights, and effectiveness.
    - Daniel Resnick, Testing, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Monroe Tests, 17th Yearbook, 1918 (copy), undated (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Notes on Teachers and Testing 1878-1900 and Newspaper Article, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Philip May, Notes on Philadelphia Testing, circa 1971 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Pittsburgh Teachers Exam 1868-1872 (copies), undated (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - 1907 Pittsburgh Suffrage for Teachers notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - "Separate Studies Show Similar Results of Teacher Effectiveness" by Ullik Rouk, R&D Report, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - 17th Yearbook, Tests and Standards Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Teacher Effectiveness, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Teacher Training in Pittsburgh, undated (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Testing Misc. Clippings, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Testing and Teacher Efficiency 1915 (copies), undated (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Testing: The Cyril Burt Question, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Testing- National, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - The Use and Abuse of Standardized Tests, The Generator, Spring, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 109)
- History of College Women in Pittsburgh Research File, 1970-1999; 1986-1988; IV.
  Series IV contains materials related to Schumacher's research about women's college experiences in the early twentieth century in Pittsburgh. This series is arranged in four subseries: Women's History in Pittsburgh, Oral History Project, Oral History Project Participant Files, and Oral History Project Cassette Tapes.
  - Women's History in Pittsburgh, 1970-1999; 1.
    The Women's History subseries includes research materials related to women's suffrage of the 1910s, the women's liberation of the 1960s and 1970s, and women's educational opportunities then and now.
    - "Admission and Attrition of Women in Graduate School" by Elizabeth Urey Baranger, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Bibliographies on Women, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Christmas Cards, National Organization for Women (N.O.W.), undated (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Executive Women's Council, Status of Women in Pittsburgh, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Feminist Historians, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - History of Women at Pitt: Reflections of a Changing Society, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Notes on the Second Year: Women's Liberation, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Powerful Women in Pittsburgh, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Sharon Johnson Trial vs. University of Pittsburgh, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - The Suffrage Cookbook from 1915(copy), undated (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - University of Pittsburgh Department of History Women's Caucus, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Women's Suffrage 1912-1917 Research, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Oral History Project, 1987-1988; 2.
    The Oral History Project subseries contains contracts, correspondence, lists, notes, and questionnaires related to oral history interviews with Pittsburgh women from Schumacher's project, "The History of Higher Education for Women in Pittsburgh: Reflections of a Changing Society."
    - Contract for Graduate Students, undated (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Interview List, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Letter of Introduction, undated (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Oral History Data Sheet, undated (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Oral History Interviews List of Candidates, undated (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Questionnaires, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Release Forms, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Thank You Letter for Oral Interviews, undated (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Marcia Frumerman, interviewer, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Oral History Manual, Bibliogrphy, and Notes prepared by Wendell Wray, November, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - Oral History, Bibliography, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Oral History Resources, undated (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Oral History Project Participant Files, 1985-1988; 3.
    The Oral History Project Participant Files subseries contains materials related to individual oral history interviews with Pittsburgh women from Schumacher's project, "The History of Higher Education for Women in Pittsburgh: Reflections of a Changing Society."
    - Agnes Starrett, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Alice Donaldson, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Ann McCandless, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Barbara F. Moran, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Caroline Sutton, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Catherine Metz, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Cecilia Schmidt Francis, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Christine Greco, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Elizabeth Kimberley, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Elizabeth McDonald, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Florence Marcus, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Frances Holland, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Genevieve Blatt, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Helen Hackett, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Helen Pool Rush, 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Helen Sawyer, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Irene Pasinski, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Janet M Flinn, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Jean Bray, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Lillian Brest, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Margaret Couvert, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Martha Rosen, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Mary Cole, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Nancy Lee, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Peggy Donaldson, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Rachel Donaldson, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Savina Skewis, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Sunny Pickering, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Thelma Nelson Wofford, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Vee Toner, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Viola Grove Patterson and Adelaide Grove McKinney, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Lynn Davidman (Box 5, Folder 31a)
    - Mary Greenwald (Box 5, Folder 31b)
  - Oral History Project: Cassette Tapes, 1986-1988; 4.
    The Oral History Project: Cassette Tapes subseries contains recordings of the oral history interviews, in addition to interviews with Schumacher for local radio stations.
    - Genevieve Blatt, November 19, 1987 (Box 6, Cassette 1-2)
      Genevieve Blatt (1913-1996) was interviewed by Carolyn Schumacher for approximated 90 minutes. Blatt discussed early family life and business, her parochial education at St. Francis DeSales Catholic School in McKees Rocks and Sacred Heart in Pittsburgh. Blatt graduated from the University of Pittsburgh where she received a scholarship, she discusses her experience at Pitt and discusses Chancellor Bowman and Dean Thyrsa Amos, the debating team, and Women's Athletic Association. Later, she graduated from the University of Pittsburgh Law School and would become a Judge in the Court of Common Pleas and later a Commonwealth Judge. She discusses her campaigns and dealings with Judge Michael Mussmanno.
    - Anna Loomis McCandless, June 30, 1988 (Box 6, Cassette 3)
      Anna Loomis McCandless (1897-1996) was interviewed for approximately 63 minutes discussing her family and education. McCandless graduated from Carnegie Tech's Margaret Morrison School for Women in 1919, having taken secretarial courses, served as her Junior Class President, and participated in the school's activities to support the war effort. McCandless comically discusses stories concerning her mother's comments on Margaret Sanger's visit to Pittsburgh and McCandless's 1929 trip to Russia. Annette Baier was interviewed about her chosen career path for approximately 90 minutes. Baier, a philosophy professor at the University of Pittsburgh, was born in New Zealand and speaks of the cultural differences which have shaped her educational experience growing up and after she moved to the United States. Speaks about the benefits of being a woman in her field in addition to some of the challenges created by traditional female expectations.
    - Annette Baier, November 16, 1987 (Box 6, Cassette 4)
      Annette Baier was interviewed about her chosen career path for approximately 90 minutes. Baier, a philosophy professor at the University of Pittsburgh, was born in New Zealand and speaks of the cultural differences which have shaped her educational experience growing up and after she moved to the United States. Speaks about the benefits of being a woman in her field in addition to some of the challenges created by traditional female expectations.
    - Bess Kimberly, June 10, 1988 (Box 6, Cassette 5)
      Bess Kimberly was interviewed by Carolyn Schumacher for approximately 80 minutes. Kimberly discussed her early education years, family, work at Horne's Department Store, and profession as a teacher in rural and cosmopolitan settings, including teaching Americanization courses in a Steel Mill town. Kimberly attended Kent College but transferred and graduated from Carnegie Tech (Margaret Morrison) in 1928 with a degree in Drama in order to teach costume design, which she taught for forty years.
    - Christine E. Greco, April 28; May 7, 1988 (Box 6, Cassette 6-7)